# Nduka-Eze Uzoma Ariguzo

301-357-5385 | u.ariguzo.ua@gmail.com | Github | Medium-Blog | LinkedIn | codeguzo.com

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Flatiron School graduate experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux with a background in Psychology and Family Science. I enthusiastically bring strong skills in team-building, communication, debugging, data analysis, and leadership which help progressive companies succeed. My strong background in STEM, along with my creativity and drive to succeed, has led me to love programming and building software.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Git, JSON, Microsoft Suites, Adobe

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Sports Programming Network (SPN) - Github - Backend | Github - Frontend | Demo

Sports news web application for your up-to-date sports stories.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, teams, players, and leagues.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side and bcrypt server-side.
- Used multiple APIs and Nokogiri Web Scraping to upload and display media throughout the application.
- Managed state and user experience with React for scalability.
- Implemented the user interface with fully CSS styling using Semantic-UI and Bootstrap frameworks.

## Bassy Jobs - Github-Backend | Github-Frontend | Demo

A job seeking app designed to help job seekers find jobs and help companies list new jobs for hire.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, company, and job listings.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side and bcrypt server-side.
- Utilized components and their life cycles, props, and states via Reacts' structural hierarchy for scalability.
- Implemented the user interface with fully CSS styling using Semantic-UI.

# AnimalGram - Github-Backend | Github-Frontend | Demo

Social media platform for users to share their pets' pictures.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, posts, organizations, likes, comments, and friends.
- Developed the frontend reactivity and user experience completely in vanilla Javascript.
- Utilized localStorage to funnel information across the web application.
- Implemented the user interface with fully CSS styling.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

College Park, MD **MARE** 07/2018 - Current

Marketing Staff / Business Analyst

- Writes and designs marketing emails(product and content promotions) using MailChimp.
- Markets and communicates the brand across multiple social media platforms.
- Implements new ideas to ensure overall success using brand imaging.

### **University of Maryland Lutheran Campus Ministry**

Program Assistant

College Park, MD 08/2018 - 08/2019

- Worked as overall IT support for ministry needs.
- Planned for, maintained, and created a web presence for the ministry.
- Organized and spearheaded community outreach programs.

# **Young Adults in Global Mission Program**

Program Manager

Victoria, Australia 07/2017 - 06/2018

- Taught technology workshops using Windows/MAC OS.
- Developed visuals for community events using HTML/CSS.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Washington, D.C 03/2020 - 06/2020 Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

# **University of Maryland College Park**

Bachelor's of Arts Psychology, Family Science

College Park, MD Graduated 05/2017